A Guide to the Records of WRVA Radio Station 1925-1968
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Series III: Walter R. Bishop Files 1925-1963
  - Speeches of Senator Byrd 1948-1958 (Box 80)
  - Other Political Material (Box 81)
    A27-11A
  - Integration- Mass Resistance (Box 81)
  - Political Material (Box 81)
  - Political Campaign 1957 (Box 81)
  - Integration (Box 81)
  - Segregation (Box 81)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous Station Files 1933-1962
  - (Alden) Aaroe (Box 82)
    A27-11B
  - Advertisers on WRVA 1960 (Box 82)
  - Advertising and Sales Promotion ca. 1962 (Box 82)
  - Agency Visits (Box 82)
  - WRVA's 35th Anniversary (Box 82)
  - WRVA's 40th Anniversary (Box 82)
  - WRVA Station Announcers 1946 (Box 82)
  - Announcement of Appointment Sales Meeting ca. 1950 (Box 82)
  - Announcement Study (Box 82)
  - Artist Bureau Agreement Form (Box 82)
  - Availabilities- Prepared by Radio Sales 1950 (Box 82)
  - BBD and O Audience Coverage- Cost Guide 1964 (Box 82)
  - BC Powders and Tablets 1933 (Box-folder 82)
  - BMB Station Audience Report Study #2 1949 Spring (Folder 82)
  - BMB Virginia 1947 (Box 82)
  - BMB Station Audience Report Study #1 1946 (Box 82)
  - BMB Area Reprint SR and D 1949-1950 (Box 82)
  - Barn Dance, New Dominion 1957 (Box 82)
  - Billboard Poster Advertising (Box 82)
  - Comparison of BMB Listening: Areas of WRVA- Richmond and WTAR- Norfolk 1951 (Box 82)
  - BMB Penetration Measurement in City of Norfolk (Box 82)
  - BMB Station Audience Report on WRVA 1946 (Box 82)
  - BMB Station Audience Report on WTAR 1949 (Box 83)
    A27-11C
  - Brand Name Accounts (Box 83)
  - Hi-Fi with Frank Brooks; Late Date with Frank Brooks 1957 (Box 83)
  - Budget Information 1950-1953 (Box 83)
  - WRVA Calendars 1940-1942 (Box 83)
  - The Commonwealth Magazine 1962 (Box 83)
  - The Commonwealth Magazine 1964 (Box 83)
  - Calling All Cooks ca. 1930s (Folder 83)
  - CBS: Competitive Media Information 1958 (Box 83)
  - CBS/Spot Selling 1958 (Folder 83)
  - Christmas Cards 1956-1957 (Folder 83)
  - City Limits 1959 Feb. (Box 83)
  - CBS Directory 1946 (Box-folder 83)
  - CBS Network Stations Index 1945-1949 (Box 83)
  - CBS Radio Spot Sales Radio Stations Representatives 1959 (Box 83)
  - CBS Special Information (Box 83)
  - CBS Station Schedule 1946 Oct 15 (Box 83)
  - Jack Clements News; Another Extra 1957, 1958 (Box 83)
  - Commercial Religious Program Questionnaire (Box 83)
  - WRVA Contracts (Box 83)
  - WRVA Package Contracts (Box 83)
  - Contract Modification Forms (Box 83)
  - Coverage Maps 1939, 1940, 1941, 1944, 1946, 1949, 1955, 1957, 1962 (Folder 83)
  - Lou Dean, Music Til Morning 1957 (Box 83)
  - WRVA Dialogs 1941-1952 (Box 84)
    A27-11D
  - WRVA Dialogs, 11 issues missing 1953 Oct. - 1956 April (Folder 84)
  - Diary Study Maps 1948 (Box 84)
  - Dinner Bell Cook Book (Box 84)
  - Dinner Winner 1955 (Box 84)
  - Esso- 10 Years with WRVA 1935-1945 (Box 84)
  - Family Radio Diary (Benson and Benson, Inc.) - sample copy (Box 84)
  - WRVA Field Intensity Contours, Norfolk, Portsmouth 1939 (Box 84)
  - Fifty-one out of Fifty-five, or How Good Can You Get (Box 84)
  - WRVA Figures and Figures (Folder 84)
  - First and Merchants National Bank (Box 84)
  - Bill Freeland Show (Box 84)
  - Gerson Study 1960- Walter Gerson and Associates, Inc. (Box 84)
  - Gerson Report Replies (Box 84)
  - Governor's Letter 1960 (Box 84)
  - Group Buying Plan (Box 84)
  - HPL- Mark Evans (Box 84)
  - HPL- Lew Martin (Box 85)
    A27-11E
  - Irby Hollans- Let's Talk Business 1957 (Box 85)
  - Hooper Formulae (Box 85)
  - Hooper- Miscellaneous Information (Box 85)
  - Hooper War Conference, Chicago 1943 April 27 (Box 85)
  - Hooper- Circulation Midwinter 1945 (Box 85)
  - Hooper- Comprehensive 1946 Summer (Box 85)
  - Hooper- Comprehensive 1946-1947 Fall-Winter, 1947-1948 Fall-Winter (Box-folder 85)
  - Hooper Selectional Ratings 1943 Fall - 1946 April (Box 85)
  - Hooper Norfolk 1943 Midwinter - 1950 February (Box 85)
  - Hooper Richmond 1941 Dec. - 1944 Feb. (Box 86)
    A27-11F
  - Hooper Richmond 1943 Dec. - 1946 Feb. (Box 86)
  - Hooper Richmond #15-22 1945 Dec. to 1948 Sept. (Box 86)
  - Hooper Richmond #23-27 1948 Oct. - 1950 April (Box 86)
  - Hooper Reprints - Highest Average Hooperating in U.S.A.; Thank You Richmond; WRVA Tops in Richmond (Box 86)
  - Hooper 1962-1964 (Box 86)
  - WRVA Horror File ca. 1952-1954 (Box 87)
    A27-11G
  - Horror File 1955 (Box 87)
  - WRVA- How Richmond Listens 1938 (Box 87)
  - I- Alphabetical (Box 87)
  - Katz Survey on WRVA- Radio Quiz 1946 (Folder 87)
  - L- Alphabetical (Box 87)
  - Mail Maps 1959 and 1960 (Box 87)
  - Mail Maps 1963 and 1965 (Box 87)
  - Broadcasting and Telecasting 1951 (Box 87)
  - WRVA Market Data Handbook 1943 (Box 87)
  - Market Data Handbook 1943 (Box 87)
  - Market Data 1947-1960 (Box 87)
  - MCS Market Coverage WRVA 1957 (Box 87)
  - Miscellaneous ca. 1936-1945 (Box 88)
    A27-11H
  - Movietown Radio Theatre (Box 88)
  - Murdock (Box 88)
  - NAB- Code Authority Monitoring (Box 88)
  - NARTB Program Log Recommendations (Box 88)
  - Negro Listening Habits in Richmond, Va. 1951 (Box 88)
  - The New Dominion (Box 88)
  - WRVA News (Box 88)
  - Newspaper Circulation/Chain Stories 1953 (Box 88)
  - Newspaper Research- Households (Box 88)
  - Newspaper Yearly Expenditures, Open Rate 1953 (Box 88)
  - WRVA News- Passage (Box 88)
  - NCS 1961 (Box 88)
  - Nielson #2, S-F WI-1 (Box 88)
  - Nielson Per Cent Penetration (Box 88)
  - WRVA's 50-100% Area Circulation of Newspapers (Folder 88)
  - A Comparison of Radio and TV Efficiency in Virginia (Box 88)
  - No Cellophane, No Pink Ribbon (Box 88)
  - Coverage in Norfolk Area (Box 88)
  - Old Dominion Barn Dance (Box 88)
  - The Virginia Foodsman (Box 88)
  - Old Dominion Barn Dance folders (Box 88)
  - Old Dominion Barn Dance (Box 89)
    A27-11I
  - Old Dominion Barn Dance (Box 89)
  - On the Go 1958 (Box 89)
  - On the Go 1958 (Box 89)
  - National Representative Analysis and Recommendations (Box 89)
  - Peters, Griffin, Woodward, Inc.- Indoctrination 1959 (Box 89)
  - PGW- Promotion of Station (Box 89)
  - Pictures- miscellaneous (Box 89)
  - Old Political Releases (Box 89)
  - Political Rates (Box 89)
  - Political 1946 (Box 89)
  - Political 1946 (Box 89)
  - Political 1948 (Box 89)
  - Political 1949 (Folder 89)
  - Political 1950 (Box 90)
    A27-11J
  - Political 1951 (Box 90)
  - Political 1952-a (Box 90)
  - Political 1952-b (Box 90)
  - Political 1953 (Box 90)
  - Political 1954 (Box 90)
  - Political, B-1 PO-1 1957 (Box 90)
  - Political Rates, B-1 PO-2 to 1957 (Box 90)
  - Post-Midnight (Box 90)
  - Thru 24-Sheet Poster Advertising (Box 90)
  - Power that Knew What it Wanted (Box 90)
  - Sample Representation Poster (Box 90)
  - Presentations 1955 (Box 90)
  - Program Information 1957 (Box 90)
  - Programming Efficiency Index (Box 90)
  - Program Schedule 1947 (Box 90)
  - Program Schedules 1948 (Box 90)
  - Program Schedule 1949 (Box 90)
  - Program Schedules 1951 (Box 90)
  - Program Schedules 1952 (Box 90)
  - Program Schedules 1953 (Box 90)
  - Program Schedules 1954 (Box 91)
    A27-11K
  - Program Schedules 1955 (Box 91)
  - Program Schedules 1956 (Box 91)
  - Program Schedules 1957 (Box 91)
  - Program Schedules 1958 (Box 91)
  - Program Schedules 1959 (Box 91)
  - Program Schedules 1960-1964 (Box 91)
  - Program Schedules 1965-1967 (Folder 91)
  - Programs 1959 (Folder 91)
  - Pulse Reports 1950 (Box 91)
  - Pulse Reports 1951 Jan. - June (Box 92)
    A27-11L
  - Pulse Reports 1951 July - Dec. (Box 92)
  - Pulse Reports 1952 Jan. - June (Box 92)
  - Pulse Reports and special study of Hampton 1952 July - Dec. (Box 92)
  - Pulse Newspaper Advertising Study- Salt Lake Newspapers 1955 (Box 92)
  - Pulse Reports 1955 Jan. - June (Box 92)
  - Pulse Reports 1955 July - Dec. (Box 92)
  - Pulse Reports plus Cumulative Pulse Audience Radio Ratings for Richmond Metro Area 1956 July - Dec.; 1956 Nov. (Box-folder 93)
    A27-11M
  - Pulse Reports 1957 Jan. - June (Box 93)
  - Pulse Reports plus Richmond Negro Audience Survey 1957 July - Dec. (Folder 93)
  - Pulse Reports 1958 Jan. - June (Box 93)
  - Pulse Reports 1958 July - Dec. (Box-folder 93)
    A27-11M plus (1) Total Audience Survey for 40-County Retail Trading Zone; (2) Audience Composition; (3) Verifak Surveys Report; (4) 40-County Post Midnight Audicne; (5) Charlottesville Audience
  - Pulse Reports 1959 (Box 93)
    A27-11M plus (1) Audience Composition; (2) FM Penetration; (3) Richmond Cumulative Pulse Audience
  - Pulse 1960 (Box 94)
    A27-11N
  - Pulse 1961 (Box 94)
  - Pulse 1962 (Box 94)
  - Pulse 1963 (Box 94)
  - Pulse 1964 (Box 94)
  - Pulse 1965 (Box 94)
  - Pulse 1966 (Box 94)
  - Pulse 1967 (Box 94)
  - C.T. Lucy's Political Material 1940 (Folder 95)
    A27-11O
  - Richmond Democratic Primary 1940 (Box 95)
  - WRVA Miscellany (Box 95)
  - Personal Political Correspondence 1933-1936 (Box 95)
  - State, National Legislation Proposed and Enacted ca. 1939 (Box 95)
  - Political Data 1939 (Box 95)
  - Presidential Campaign 1940 (Box 96)
    A27-11P
  - Station Miscellany 1936-1937 (Box-folder 96)
  - Personal Publicity Continuities (Folder 96)
  - Publications - Fortune, The Guardian, Richmond Christian Advocate 1939-1940 (Box 96)
  - St. Mark's Episcopal Church Correspondence 1948 (Box 97)
    A27-11Q
  - Miscellaneous (Box 97)
  - Complaint Letters - Per Inquiry, Other Offers, etc. 1949-1950 (Box 97)
  - WRVA Program Schedules, etc. 1947 (Box 97)
  - Va. Conference Orphanage/Association of Men's Bible Classes (Folder 97)
  - R.E. Lee's 150th Birthday Celebration Dramalog 1927, 1932, 1936, 1939 (Box 98)
    A27-11R
  - President's Birthday Ball [Infantile Paralysis] 1942 Jan. 30 (Box 98)
  - National Peanut Festival- Suffolk, Va. 1941 Jan. 29 (Box 98)
  - Easter and Lent (Box-folder 98)
  - Washington's Birthday (Box 98)
  - Shenendoah Apple Blossom Festival (Box-folder 98)
  - Jamestown Day May 13 (Box 98)
  - Williamsburg Celebrations (Box 98)
  - Cape Henry Pilgrimage 1942 April 26 (Box 98)
  - White Top Mountain Folk Music Festival, Abingdon, Va., mid-August (Box 98)
  - Richmond Community Fund (Folder 98)
  - Yorktown Day 1951 Oct. 19 (Box 98)
  - Thanksgiving Day (Box 98)
  - Navy Day (Box 98)
  - Christmas Season (Box-folder 98)
  - Other Anniversaries and Special Observances (Box 98)
  - White Top Mountain Talk (Box 99)
    A27-11S
  - Messages to and from Mr. Lucy et al (Box 99)
  - Memos to and from Mr. C.T. Lucy (Box 99)
  - WRVA Miscellany (Box 99)
  - WRVA History (Box 99)
  - Music (Box 99)
  - Virginia Listeners (Box 99)
  - Virginia Listeners (cont'd) 1942 (Box 99)
  - U.S. and Foreign Listeners (Box 99)
  - American School of the Air (Box 99)
  - Other Stations (Box 100)
    A27-11T
  - Reception Reports (Box 100)
  - WRVA Program Inquiries (Box 100)
  - WRVA Dialog 1946 April (Folder 100)
  - Office Memos (Box 100)
  - CBS Information (Box 100)
  - Larus Bros. Library 1941-1942 (Box 100)
  - U.S. Government (Box 100)
  - WRVA Programs 1932 (Box 100)
  - Commercial (Box 100)
  - Private, Station Employees (Folder 100)
  - Memos, Mr. Lucy, et al. (Box 100)
  - Copyright to Other Legislation, Restrictions (Box 100)
  - Lifeline (Box 100)
  - WRVA Copy (Box 100)
  - Color Television Information from CBS 1953 (Box 100)
  - Entries in WRVA 30th Anniversary Celebration Contest (Box 101)
    A27-12A
  - Entries in WRVA 30th Anniversary Celebration Contest (Box 101)
  - 30th Anniversary Contest Winners (Box 101)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 101)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 101)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 101)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 102)
    A27-12B
  - Miscellaneous Sports Items (Box 102)
  - Used Sports Thrills (Box 102)
  - Mr. Carlson 1947 (Box 103)
    A27-12C
  - Little Margie's Scrap Book, Corn Cob Pipe Club 1932 (Box 103)
  - Smoke from Corn Cob Pipe Club; Mr. Carlson Personal (Box 103)
  - Mr. Carlson: Corn Cob Pipe Club and WRVA 40th Anniversary (Box 103)
  - C.T.L. - Personal Notes from WRVA Staff 1950-1953 (Box 103)
  - WVTA, C.T.L. Desk File (Box 103)
  - C.T.L. - Testimony Exhibits, Richmond TV Corp. Hearing, Washington, D.C. 1954 March 1-12 (Box 103)
  - WRVA 30th Anniversary - Complete Program and Celebration (Box 103)
  - Historical Data, Larus and WRVA (Folder 103)
  - WRVA 20th Anniversary Program 1945 Nov 2 (Box 104)
    A27-12D
  - WRVA's 1st Anniversary 1926 (Box 104)
  - WRVA Opening Program and Dedication 1925 Nov. 2 (Monday) (Box 104)
  - Mr. Carlson, Daily Program File 1959 March 29 (Sun) (Box 104)
  - WRVA Historical Information (Box 104)
  - Old Dominion Barn Dance (Box 104)
  - WRVA Theatre (Box 104)
  - Mr. Carlson - Larus and Brothers Company (Box 104)
  - Mr. Carlson - Miscellaneous (Box 104)
  - Historical Material (Box 104)
  - Miscellaneous Items (Box 104)
  - Dialog, WRVA 1942 (Box 105)
    A27-12E
  - WRVA News Clipping, Notes and Memos - Radio (Box 105)
  - Quality Radio Group (Box 105)
  - National Association of Radio and TV Broadcasters ca. 1954-1961 (Box 105)
  - FCC (Box 105)
  - CBS (Box 105)
  - Larus Publicity (Box 105)
  - The New NBC Station-Network Plan 1935 January (Box 105)
  - Larus, Station Material (Box 105)
  - Miscellaneous Historical: Sidney Lanier, Colgate W. Darden (Box 105)
  - Holiday for Music (Folder 105)
  - Labor Unions (Box 105)
  - San Francisco (Box 105)
  - Information - History (Box 105)
  - City of Richmond 1948-1949 (Box 105)
  - Lt. Sanford Terry - Leyte Publicity (Box 105)
  - Clippings (Box 105)
  - St. Petersburg, Fla. (Box 106)
    A27-12F
  - WRVA Program Inquiries (Box 106)
  - CBS: Program Inquiries, Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 106)
  - Complaints (Box 106)
  - Complimentary (Box 106)
  - Dialog (Box 106)
  - Contests 1948-1949 (Box 106)
  - National Association of Broadcasters (Box 106)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 106)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 106)
  - Listener Mail 1955 (Box 106)
  - Miscellaneous Mail 1955
  - VAB Legislative Commission 1946-1954 (Box 106)
  - Miscellaneous Mail 1949-1950, 1953 (Box 106)
  - Appreciation 1949-1957 (Box 107)
    A27-12G
  - Appreciation 1942 (Box 107)
  - Appreciation 1941 (Box 107)
  - Appreciation 1940 (Box 107)
  - Appreciation 1939 (Box 107)
  - Appreciation 1939 (Box 107)
  - Applause 1937 (Box 107)
  - Applause 1936 (Box 107)
  - Blizzard - Complete Public Service File 1940 Jan. (Box 107)
  - American CBS School of the Air Survey 1944 (Box 108)
    A27-12H
  - American CBS School of the Air Survey 1944 (Box 108)
  - Civil War Centennial (Box 108)
  - Applications 1950-1959 (Box 108)
  - FM - WRVB - WRVC 1948-1950 (Box 108)
  - Applications 1947-1949 (Box 108)
  - Miscellaneous W.R.B. Mail re: TV 1948-1953 (Box 108)
  - Cracker Barrel Material - Political (Box 109)
    A27-12I
  - Cracker Barrel Material - Non-Political (Box 109)
  - Installation of New President of William and Mary College 1961 (Box 109)
  - American School of the Air (Box 109)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 109)
  - Programming (Box 109)
  - Philharmonic- Symphony Fans (Box 109)
  - General Station Affairs (Box 109)
  - Deferred Matters (Box 109)
  - Maintenance 1944 (Box 110)
    A27-12J
  - Historical Materials (Box 110)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 110)
  - Miscellany (Box 110)
  - Messages to and from Mr. C.T. Lucy, et. al. 1942 (Box 111)
    A27-12K
  - Continuities 1928-1929 (Box 111)
  - Criticisms, Complaints, Suggestions (Box 111)
  - Distant Listeners (Box 111)
  - War Material (Box 111)
  - Letters from Prominent People - Unusual Letters (Box 111)
  - WRVA Listener Diary Study, 3 bound volumes (Box 112)
    A27-12L
  - Printed manuals and schematic diagrams for various electronic equipment (Box 113)
    A27-12M
  - Miscellaneous correspondence 1946-1959 (Box 114)
    A27-12N
  - Church bulletins and miscellaneous printed matter 1950s (Box 114)
  - Appointment calendar, heavily annotated 1955 (Box 114)
  - Correspondence and articles (TM and printed) labeled, Miss Bertha Hewlett 1955-1956 (Box 114)
  - Pages from promotional scrapbook for chefs n.d. (Box 114)
  - Pages from promotional scrapbook re: musical programs and the Virginia Music Festival n.d. (Box 114)
  - autographed photographs: Dwight D. Eisenhower and Louisen.d.
  - Calendar with picture of U.S.S. South Dakota 1945 Jan
  - Printed Romance Map of Washington, D.C. n.d.
  - Printed A Tribute to Our Flag, Protestant Radio and Television Center award, U.S. Air Force award, set of publicity posters 1950s
  - Schematic diagrams for WE 407-A1 transmitter, etc. Blueline and photostatic copies n.d.
  - Logbooks: recorded songs aired 1930s, 2 items
  - Promotional display album 1950s
  - Alternate pages for preceding item 1950s
  - Public Service Jingles...for the 'Give, Register, and Vote' Campaign n.d., 7-inch disk, 45 rpm
    P-622 American Heritage Foundation and The Advertising Council, Inc.
  - Henrico County Commemoration, w/ Rt. Rev. F.D. Goodwin 1957 May 1, 12-inch disk, 33.3 rpm
    P-623
  - Messer - [Joseph] DiMaggio, Jack Dempsey 1961 Feb 1, 1961 Oct 24, 12-inch disk, 33.3 rpm
    P-624
- Station Logs from 1925-
  original vols. destroyed after microfilming
  - Logbook 1925 Nov - 1932 Nov (Reel 1)
    A27-12O
  - Logbook 1932 Nov - 1935 Dec (Reel 2)
  - Logbook 1936 Jan - 1937 Jul (Reel 3)
  - Logbook 1937 July - 1938 Oct (Reel 4)
  - Logbook 1938 Oct - 1939 Aug (Reel 5)
  - Logbook 1939 Aug - 1940 May (Reel 6)
  - Logbook 1940 May - 1940 Nov (Reel 7)
  - Logbook 1940 Nov - 1941 May (Reel 8)
  - Logbook 1941 May - 1941 Dec (Reel 9)
  - Logbook 1941 Dec - 1942 May (Reel 10)
  - Logbook 1942 May - 1942 Nov (Reel 11)
  - Logbook 1942 Nov - 1943 Apr (Reel 12)
  - Logbook 1943 Apr - 1943 Oct (Reel 13)
  - Logbook 1943 Oct - 1944 Apr (Reel 14)
  - Logbook 1944 Apr - 1944 Oct (Reel 15)
  - Logbook 1944 Oct - 1945 May (Reel 16)
  - Logbook 1945 May - 1945 Dec (Reel 17)
  - Logbook 1945 Dec - 1945 July (Reel 18)
  - Logbook 1945 July - 1946 March (Reel 19)
  - Logbook 1946 Mar - 1946 Oct (Reel 20)
  - Logbook 1946 Oct - 1947 Jan 2 (Reel 21)
  - Logbook 1947 Jan 3 - 1947 June 5 (Reel 22)
  - Logbook 1947 June 6 - 1947 Nov 15 (Reel 23)
  - Logbook 1947 Nov 15 - 1948 Apr 22 (Reel 24)
  - Logbook 1948 Apr 22 - 1948 Aug 13 (Reel 25)
  - Logbook 1948 Aug 13 - 1948 Oct 21 (Reel 26)
  - Logbook 1948 Oct 21 - 1948 Dec 29 (Reel 27)
    A27-12P
  - Logbook 1948 Dec 29 - 1949 Mar 9 (Reel 28)
  - Logbook 1949 Mar 9 - 1949 Apr 29 (Reel 29)
  - Logbook 1949 Apr 29 - 1949 June 27 (Reel 30)
  - Logbook 1949 June 27 - 1949 Aug 20 (Reel 31)
  - Logbook 1949 Aug 20 - 1949 Oct 14 (Reel 32)
  - Logbook 1949 Oct 14 - 1949 Dec 7 (Reel 33)
  - Logbook 1949 Dec 7 - 1950 Feb 1 (Reel 34)
  - Logbook 1950 Feb 1 - 1950 March 30 (Reel 35)
  - Logbook 1950 March 30 - 1950 June 2 (Reel 36)
  - Logbook 1950 June 2 - 1950 Aug 9 (Reel 37)
  - Logbook 1950 Aug 10 - 1950 Oct 16 (Reel 38)
  - Logbook 1950 Oct 16 - 1950 Dec 19 (Reel 39)
  - Logbook 1950 Dec 19 - 1951 March 4 (Reel 40)
  - Logbook 1951 March 4 - 1951 May 11 (Reel 41)
  - Logbook 1951 May 11 - 1951 June 21 (Reel 42)
  - Logbook 1951 June 21 - 1951 Aug 29 (Reel 43)
  - Logbook 1951 Aug 29 - 1951 Oct 11 (Reel 44)
  - Logbook 1951 Nov 5 - 1952 Jan 10 (Reel 45)
  - Logbook 1952 Jan 10 - 1952 Mar 14 (Reel 46)
  - Logbook 1952 Mar 14 - 1952 May 21 (Reel 47)
  - Logbook 1952 May 21 - 1952 July 28 (Reel 48)
  - Logbook 1952 July 28 - 1952 Oct 4 (Reel 49)
  - Logbook 1952 Oct 4 - 1952 Dec 9 (Reel 50)
  - Logbook 1952 Dec 9 - 1953 Feb 12 (Reel 51)
  - Logbook 1952 Feb 12 - 1953 Apr 17 (Reel 52)
  - Logbook 1953 Apr 17 - 1953 Jun 23 (Reel 53)
    A27-12Q
  - Logbook 1953 Jun 23 - 1953 Aug 20 (Reel 54)
  - Logbook 1953 Aug 20 - 1953 Oct 24 (Reel 55)
  - Logbook 1953 Oct 25 - 1953 Dec 29 (Reel 56)
  - Logbook 1953 Dec 29 - 1954 Mar 2 (Reel 57)
  - Logbook 1954 Mar 2 - 1954 May 13 (Reel 58)
  - Logbook 1954 May 13 - 1954 July 27 (Reel 59)
  - Logbook 1954 July 27 - 1954 Oct 11 (Reel 60)
  - Logbook 1954 Oct 11 - 1954 Dec 14 (Reel 61)
  - Logbook 1954 Dec 14 - 1955 Feb 18 (Reel 62)
  - Logbook 1955 Feb 19 - 1955 Apr 18 (Reel 63)
  - Logbook 1955 Apr 19 - 1955 June 17 (Reel 64)
  - Logbook 1955 June 17 - 1955 Aug 17 (Reel 65)
  - Logbook 1955 Aug 17 - 1955 Oct 15 (Reel 66)
  - Logbook 1955 Oct 15 - 1955 Dec 15 (Reel 67)
  - Logbook 1955 Dec 15 - 1956 Feb 27 (Reel 68)
  - Logbook 1956 Feb 1 - 1956 Mar 23 (Reel 69)
  - Logbook 1956 Mar 23 - 1956 May 3 (Reel 70)
  - Logbook 1956 May 4 - 1956 July 4 (Reel 71)
  - Logbook 1956 July 5 - 1956 Sept 11 (Reel 72)
  - Logbook 1956 Sept 11 - 1956 Nov 19 (Reel 73)
  - Logbook 1956 Nov 19 - 1957 Jan 31 (Reel 74)
  - Logbook 1957 Jan 31 - 1957 Apr 13 (Reel 75)
  - Logbook 1957 Apr 13 - 1957 June 21 (Reel 76)
  - Logbook 1957 June 21 - 1957 Aug 29 (Reel 77)
  - Logbook 1957 Aug 29 - (?) (Reel 78)
    A27-12R
  - Logbook (?) - 1957 Dec 8 (Reel 79)
  - Logbook 1957 Dec 8 - 1958 Feb 9 (Reel 80)
  - Logbook 1958 Feb 9 - 1958 Apr 11 (Reel 81)
  - Logbook 1958 Apr 11 - 1958 June 5 (Reel 82)
  - Logbook 1958 June 5 - 1958 Aug 4 (Reel 83)
  - Logbook 1958 Aug 4 - 1958 Oct 4 (Reel 84)
  - Logbook 1958 Oct 4 - 1958 Dec 5 (Reel 85)
  - Logbook 1958 Dec 5 - 1959 Feb 12 (Reel 86)
  - Logbook 1959 Feb 12 - 1959 Apr 20 (Reel 87)
  - Logbook 1959 Apr 20 - 1959 June 16 (Reel 88)
  - Logbook 1959 June 16 - 1959 Aug 6 (Reel 89)
  - Logbook 1959 Aug 7 - 1959 Sept 30 (Reel 90)
  - Logbook 1959 Sept 30 - 1959 Nov 21 (Reel 91)
  - Logbook 1959 Nov 21 - 1960 Jan 15 (Reel 92)
  - Logbook 1960 Jan 15 - 1960 Mar 12 (Reel 93)
  - Logbook 1960 Mar 13 - 1960 Apr 29 (Reel 94)
  - Logbook 1960 Apr 30 - 1960 June 13 (Reel 95)
  - Logbook 1960 June 13 - 1960 July 24 (Reel 96)
  - Logbook 1960 July 25 - 1960 Sept 5 (Reel 97)
  - Logbook 1960 Sept 5 - 1960 Oct 17 (Reel 98)
  - Logbook 1960 Oct 17 - 1960 Nov 25 (Reel 99)
  - Logbook 1960 Nov 26 - 1961 Jan 4 (Reel 100)
  - Logbook 1961 Jan 5 - 1961 Apr 6 (Reel 101)
  - Logbook 1961 Apr 7 - 1961 July 3 (Reel 102)
    A27-12S
  - Logbook 1961 July 3 - 1961 Sept 26 (Reel 103)
  - Logbook 1961 Dec 25 - 1962 Mar 28 (Reel 105)
  - Logbook 1962 Mar 29 - 1962 June 20 (Reel 106)
  - Logbook 1962 Jun 21 - 1962 Sept 12 (Reel 107)
  - Logbook 1962 Sept 13 - 1962 Dec 31 (Reel 108)
- Tape Recordings of Material from WRVA Archives, All tapes, with exception of no. 1, are recorded on one side only. All tapes should be played at 3 3/4 ips.
  - Tape 1
    T 102 Va. State Chamber of Commerce Show- 37th Anniversary Talk Show with Dick Gillis, C.T. Lucy and Walter Bishop about the first days of WRVA in 1925 with 1000 watts. Some remarks about Ladysmith, Caroline Co., where Lucy now lives. Then on to the String Band run by various members of the Lucy family (Mandolin and Guitar Club). Many remarks about C.T. Lucy by Bishop. Remarks about changes in radio over the years. Growth from 425 stations to over 5000 in U.S. Not a commerical station at the beginning. Larus and Bros. wanted to be a community station. Invited community groups from Va., Md., and N.C. to perform. Went commerical about 2 1/2 years later because cost of operating was high as hours extended. 1962 Nov 11 0-190
    Senator Harry Byrd Funeral and Chris Cabell comments on the preparation for the funeral of Monitor.(191-228)
    Chris Cabell naming of Sen. Harry Bryd's pallbearers.(228-238)
    Chris Cabell: an obituary of Harry F. Byrd together with description of funeral and clips of service.(239-306)
    Larry Dodd: obituary on day of death includes a clip of Gov. Godwin commenting at a breakfast, off-the-cuff, when he learned of Sen. Bryd's death. Also includes Godwin's later formal statement; Albertis Harrison's statement- live; J. Lindsay Almond's statement- live; William Tuck's statement- live; Colgate Darden's statement- live. Then switches to clips from WRVA archives to illustrate Byrd's life by comments from others: (1) Bernard Baruch; (2) Mike Mansfield; (3) Everett Dirkson; (4) Lyndon B. Johnson. Then clips of Byrd himself. (306-473)